Ren Burnett

Adaptable fullstack developer with attention to detail and the ability to empathetically and thoughtfully collaborate. Excited to bring traits gained in six years as a precision technician to help shape quality code. Enthusiastic about learning new technologies/languages and developing helpful, practical software.

PROJECTS

Grasher — Food Inventory Tracker

grasher-food-tracker-frontend.herokuapp.com
github.com/renburnett/grasher-app-frontend

- React frontend, Rails backend, Semantic-React UI for styling
- Login: r@r.com Pass: 123

KEXP Song Favoriter — *Track User's Favorite Songs*

kexp-song-favoriter-rails.herokuapp.com github.com/renburnett/kexp song favoriter

- Static web app implemented with Ruby on Rails
- Queries KEXP endpoint
- Persists songs and users to Postgres DB

Chatter — *ChatRoom WebApp* github.com/kel29/chat-frontend

github.com/kel29/chat-server

- React frontend, Rails API backend
- ActionCables and React ActionCable Provider to handle connections
- Bootstrap used for styling

EXPERIENCE

Banana App (BGP), Junior Fullstack Developer — Seattle github.com/FoodIsLifeBGP/banana-rn banana app

JANUARY 2020 - CURRENT

- React Native frontend written in TypeScript, Rails backend
- Hosted on Heroku

Currently contributing to Banana App code base. Banana App is an open-source, not-for-profit project of The Be Good Foundation. Aim is to reduce hunger by simplifying the food donation process.

Microsoft via WTIA, Software Developer Apprentice — Redmond

NOVEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018

Worked on OS Bluetooth Quality team for first six months where I created a Bluetooth Radio Provisioning tool that is now used to set up mock peripherals for testing against the Windows OS. Reduced the time spent testing OS by one to two hours. The remaining six months was spent on a Data Science team and mostly scripted in Python. Enjoyed learning from teammates and problem solving alongside them.

Boeing, Composite Technician and Team Lead — Everett

MARCH 2011 - APRIL 2017

Team leader of a fast-paced seven person Composite Repair Team. Interactions with teammates were professional, respectful and fun. Ensured that majority of deadlines were met but not at the expense of quality work.

Seattle, WA (206) 669-7498 renardburnett@gmail.com github.com/renburnett linkedin.com/in/renard-burnett-ii renburnett.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript
TypeScript
React/React Native
HTML5/CSS
Git
C#/ASP.NET
Python
Ruby on Rails
MVC Architecture
SQL
Azure

EDUCATION

Flatiron School — Software Engineering Certificate

AUGUST 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

 Functional and Object Oriented Programming with JavaScript and Ruby.

Code Fellows — Fullstack Developer Certificate

JUNE 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2017

- Learned to design and create single page web applications from scratch using MVC architecture.
- Worked with string, array, object data structures and algorithms to solve code challenges with vanilla JavaScript.

TLG Learning — C# Developer Certificate

SEPTEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2017

 Learned how to leverage concepts such as inheritance, method overriding, interfaces, and object hierarchies in C#.